He's taken a real turn for the worse since this morning.
今朝がら特に酷くなって
I've taken him to a number of doctors,
but the cause is still unknown.
何人もの医者に見せたんですが原因は分からず
As someone from a caravan fleet
that makes stops at countries around the world,
国々を巡る船団キャラバンの方なら
I was thinking perhaps you'd know
a good way to treat him.
何か良い治療法を知ってるんじゃないかと
Be that as it may... I am just a pharmacist.
とは言っても私は薬師ですし
In any case, let's get him to the caravan's medical ship.
とにかくキャラバンの治療船に運びましょう
First of all, we need to get his fever down,
まずは 熱を下げないと命が助かっても
or else his body will be permanently damaged
even if he does survive.
身体がイカれてしまいます
How's Kiyui doing?
キユイどうなの
We're going to head to the caravan fleet for now.
船団キャラバンに行ってくる
Take care of things here for me.
あとは頼んだぞ
Kiyui...
キユイ 今日の誕生日のお祝いすごく楽しみにしていたのに
He was so very much looking forward to
his birthday celebration today...
No way... He can't possibly...
まさか あいつ
Huh?
The "Birthday-Death Disease"?
「誕生日に死ぬ病」
Yes.
ええ 最近生まれた日に命を落とすものがやけに多くて
Lately, an awful lot of people have died
on the same day of the year they were born...
And there's a rumor going around
that it's the work of some disease.
それが病の仕業じゃないかと噂になってるんです
Please take a look.
見てください
A funeral?
お葬式
Yes...
The deceased's ashes are returned to the Abyss
together with Eternal Fortune flowers.
トコシエコウの花とともに灰をアビスへ帰すんです
That funeral is for someone
who passed away from this same thing...
あの葬式の故人もそれです
Huh?
In fact, before this child got sick,
実は この子の前に
two others at the orphanage died
due to some unknown medical condition.
孤児院でも原因不明の症状で二人なくなっています
Counting suspicious deaths alone, the total is five now.
不審な死だけ数えれば5人です
All of them were orphans
whose birthdays were unknown...
皆誕生日のわからない孤児たちでした
Something as absurd as all this...
そんな理不尽なものなど 眉唾ものだと思いたいですが
I'd like to think it's just a stupid made-up story, but...
Hey, you alright now?
お前大丈夫か
Yeah...
Where... am I?
ここ どこ
I didn't even do anything.
私 何もしていないんですけどね
どういうことなんでしょうか
What could this possibly mean?
This boy is so healthy
it's hard to believe he even had a fever.
この子 熱が出てたことがおかしいくらい健康なんですよ
At this point, I suppose it is some kind of curse or spell...
ここまでくると もはや呪いや呪いの類ね
Which reminds me, there's been something
like it before - something completely absurd...
そいういえばあったわね とびきり理不尽で
The mysterious "Great Pit of the Netherworld,"
which is itself referred to as a curse...
まさに呪いって言われる
正体不明の「奈落の大穴」
Longing seizes people more powerfully than poison
and more deeply than illness.
憧れは毒より強く病より深く人を捕らえる
Once it catches hold of you,
there is absolutely no escape.
一度捕まると決して逃げられない
That is quite a "curse," and yet the adventurers
all willingly devote themselves to its pursuit.
それはまるで「呪い」だが
冒険者たちは皆 進んで身を投じてゆく
For them, a life without longing
is more terrifying than death itself.
彼らにとって 憧れのない人生は 死よりも恐ろしいのだ
Daremo ga sakaraezu ni mogutteiku
誰もが逆らえずに潜っていく
その目を灯火より輝かせて
Sono me o tomoshibi yori kagayakasete
Mezasu saki wa fukaku
目指す先は深く まっすぐに迷い込む
Massugu ni mayoikomu
Kuchiaketa naraku no wana
口開けた奈落の罠 真実の跡を追いかけよう
Shinjitsu no ato o oikakeyou
Ima kotae ga mitsukaru nara zenbu nakushitemo ii
今答えが 見つかるなら 全部失くしてもいい
Sono koe o hanasanai youni kodama ga mada hibiiteru
その声を 離さないように 木霊がまだ響いてる
羅針盤はずっと 闇を指したまま逃げ場のない 方へ
Rashinban wa zutto
Yami o sashita mama
Nigeba no nai
Hou e
Sore ga noroi demo
それが呪いでも 鼓動は本物
Kodou wa honmono
二度と憧れは 止まらない
Nidoto akogare wa tomaranai
The True Nature of the Curse
It wasn't this place...
ここではない 似たどこかの景色
Was it the scenery of somewhere similar?
Also, that voice...
それにあの声 聞き間違いじゃなければ
If I'm not mistaken...
that was one of my own...
あのは僕の 僕の記憶 なのか
my own memories...
wasn't it?
In that case, the one
who was mourning for Lyza was...
なら ライザーを弔ったのも
Did I bury her?
僕が埋めたのか
No, Ozen said, "No one was buried there."
いや オーゼンは「遺体はなかった」と
What does it all mean...?
一体どう言う
S-stop it!
や やめろ
Get away from Riko!
リコから離れろ
I said stop it! You little...
やめろって
このっ
Just relax.
安心しなよ
Mitty won't attack humans.
ミーティは人を襲わないぜ
Normally Mitty doesn't get emotionally attached
to visitors, though.
普段客には懐かないんだけどな
They're close in age, so maybe Mitty
took a liking to her.
歳が近いし気に入ったのかもな
Before becoming like this,
Mitty was also a girl, you see.
ミーティもこうなる前は 女の子だったんだぜ
Huh?!
M-Mitty...?
ミ ミーティ
Just please don't eat the mushrooms, okay?
キノコは食べたりしないでくれよ
She's not one to treat others so cruelly.
そんな邪険にするもんじゃないぜ
It was thanks to Mitty, after all,
that we got the poison out.
ミーティのおかげで毒も抜けたんだしな
Huh?
What do you mean?
どういうことだ
That medicine was made by injecting Mitty
with an orbed-piercer's poison.
あの薬は ミーティにタマウガチの毒を打って作ったのさ
な なに
What?!
Why'd you do such a thing?
なんだってそんな事を
Mitty has the ability to neutralize poisons all on her own.
ミーティは毒を自分で治せるのさ すごいだろ
Amazing, huh?
So I then used her blood
to produce the medicine, you see.
その血を材料に薬をこしらえたってわけだ
Nanachi, who exactly were you two
before you became Hollows?
ナナチ 君らは 「なれはて」になる前は何者だったんだ
んなぁ それ聞いちゃう
Oh... You really wanna ask that?
It's best you don't.
やめときなよ
If you do, you're gonna end up wanting to help us.
聞いたらオイラのこと 助けたくなっちゃうぜ
Wh-what?!
な 何を
You saved us, didn't you?!
君は恩人ではないか
Of course I'll try to help-
助けぐらい当たり前
Alright!
よしっ
Look, it's done!
ほれ できたぞ
My special Netherworld Stew!
オイラ特製の
奈落シチューだ
お前もやっとけ
Go on and try some.
Here!
ほれ
It looks like sticky... mud...
粘りのある 泥
This... was made with the ingredients I collected, correct?
これ さっきの材料使っているんだよな
Don't worry about, um, how it looks.
見た目はまぁ 気にすんな
It has an oddly fishy scent...
妙になま臭い 一体何の匂いだ
What the heck kinda smell is that anyway?
I'm going to take some for you too, Mitty,
so you can munch on it later.
後でモグモグできるように ミーティの分も取っといてやるからな
Some kind of discharge?!
分泌物
何だこれは
What the heck is this?
Was this truly made using those ingredients?
本当にあの材料から出来たものなのか
Huh?
おま まずかった
You... think it's bad?
Nanachi, you normally eat this stuff?
ナナチ 君は普段からこれを
W-well...
ま まあ
Come on, don't look at me like that...
なんだよぉ そんな目で見るなよぉ
お オイラ ほら 美味しい料理とか食べたことないし
I... Look, I've never even gotten to eat
tasty food before...
リコが目覚めてこれを食べたら
If Riko wakes up and eats this...
this time she's really going to die.
今度こそ死んでしまう
I've got no choice! I have to cook myself!
やるしかない 僕が料理を
Well... if you don't like it, don't eat it.
んなぁ 嫌なら食うなよぉ
Oh, I see...
なるほどなぁ
So she's looking for her mother who descended
to the bottom of the netherworld, huh?
奈落の底に潜った母ちゃんを探しにねぇ
Still, we're talking about a girl
with an insatiable curiosity
しかし 好奇心旺盛な女の子と
and a piece of junk who can't regain
even one of his important memories...
めぼしい記憶一つ取り戻せないボンコツがなぁ
You did well just making it this far.
お前らよくここまで来れたな
Or should I say, it was actually quite hopeless...
つーか 実際どうにもなってなかったか
Nanachi, please tell me...
ナナチ 教えてくれ
You...
君は 君は「アビスの呪い」を回避する方法を知っているのではないか
You know of a way to evade
the Curse of the Abyss, don't you?
Well...
んなぁ 「見えない」奴に教えたところでなあ
even if I was to explain it
to someone like you who can't "see" it...
Besides, it's also my personal secret.
オイラの秘密でもあるしなぁ
I beg you! We need to know!
頼む 必要なんだ
Even so...
そうは言ってもなぁ
僕に出来ることなら どんな取引でも応じる だから
If it's in my power, I'll do whatever you want in return!
So, please!
Hey, don't get so close!
んなぁ 近づくなよ
Alright then...
そうだな
let's give it a shot.
試してみるか
If you insist...
しょーがねーな 特別に体験させてやるよ
I'll make an exception
and let you experience it yourself.
Alright...
よしっと
Hey, you get under here, too.
ほれ お前も入りな
What is this thing?
これは一体
"Fog Weave," a grade-3 Relic.
三級遺物 「霧織り」
Well, it's basically a super thin piece of cloth.
ま すんげえ薄い布切れだ
It's just like this, I suppose.
丁度こんな感じだな
What is?
何がだ
The true nature of the Curse of the Abyss.
「アビスの呪い」の正体だよ
なに
What?!
It's floaty in the same kind of way.
こんな感じのふわふわがな
With layer piled upon layer, it blankets us!
何重にも重なってオイラ達を覆ってるのさ
Even if you touch it, you won't feel it,
nor can you see it...
触れても感じず 見えもせず
When we move, it moves along with us.
オイラ達が動けば合わせて動き
息をしただけで流れができる
Simply breathing is enough to alter its flow.
S-so when you touch it,
that's when you're hit by the Curse of the Abyss?
そ それに触れると「アビスの呪い」にかかるのか
It's not like that.
そんな事は無え
Huh?
When you touch it, it simply warps...
触れても撓むだけだ
丁度この布みたいにな
Just like this cloth.
So then...
なら なら どうすればかかるというんだ
So then what makes you get hit with the Curse?
それは こう
That would be... doing this...
Kinda like... this.
こんな感じで
Once you break through,
the symptoms hit you all at once.
突き抜けちまうと症状が一気に出る
If it's just something like your fingertips,
you'll hardly be affected...
手の先とかならほぼ影響ねーけど
But when it comes to your head or chest...
頭とか胸とか命に近そうなトコが通ると
If any part of you that's vital to life
passes through, then...
Well, as you've seen, something seriously
not good will end up happening...
まあ 見てきたようにろくでもないことになるわけだ
お 降りる時はどうなってるんだ
Wh-what happens when you descend?
Well, passing on through from above is nice and smooth.
んなぁ 上から通り抜ける分にはするりだ
It's got a flow to it similar to "inverted thorns,"
making it so you can't get out once you've entered.
入ったら出られない「さかトゲ」のような流れがあるんだ
Look. It's something like this.
ほれ こんな感じだな
It's just like a trap for catching prey.
まるで獲物を捕らえる罠さ
What exactly is it?
何なんだ その悪意み満ちたふわふわは
That malice-filled floaty thing, I mean.
Still don't get it?
わかんね
It's the force field.
「力場」だよ
The one that carries light to the subterranean world
while at the same time obstructing observation of it...
地下世界に光を運び 同時に観測を阻む
The one that continues to stubbornly guard the
netherworld's true nature and the order within it...
奈落の秩序と正体を頑なに守り続ける
That's the mysterious force field I speak of.
正体不明の力場だ
Filling every corner of this pit,
it's the very blood of the Abyss, so to speak.
縦穴を隈無く満たす 言わばアビスの血液
And that is the true nature of the Curse of the Abyss...
そいつが「アビスの呪い」の正体さ
There's nowhere to escape from it.
逃げ場なんてどこにもありゃしない
B-but, Nanachi, didn't you say the Curse
wasn't present around your hideout?!
だ だがナナチのアジト周辺は「呪い」が無いではないか
Well...
この場所見つけるのは苦労したんだぜ
I took great pains to find this place.
The force field gets weaker the farther away
you get from the vertical shaft.
縦穴から遠いほど力場は弱くなるんだ
I-is that so?
そ そうなのか
After descending this far,
don't you have somewhat of a feel for it?
ここまで潜って来たなら
なんとなく身に覚えねぇ
Well, I suppose there aren't many places
as stable as this one.
ま こんなに安定した場所 そう無いけどな
That area around the Seeker Camp also...
シーカーキャンプ付近も
I get it now...
そういうことか
Also, the force field is sensitive
to the movements of living things.
それとこの力場
生き物の動きに敏感でな
It even responds to their very consciousnesses
and alters its flow.
意識にまで反応して流れを作るんだ
Do you get it?
分かるか 意識が読めれば動きも読める
If you can read something's consciousness,
you can anticipate its movements.
Orbed-piercers don't have great intuition...
タマウガチは感がいいんじゃねぇ
They can actually predict the future.
未来予知が出来るのさ
The deeper you go, the denser and stronger
the force field becomes.
力場は深ければ深いほど より濃く強くなる
奈落の底に挑むってのは
So challenging the netherworld's bottom means
continuing on a path brimming with a deadly curse,
この先死の呪いが充満する中で
未来を読む捕食者を相手にしていくってことだ
while also going up against predators
that can predict the future.
Sounds positively delightful, right?
なかなか愉快だろ
H-how in the world do cave raiders
manage to still press on?
た 探窟家達は一体どいうやって進んでいるんだ
Who knows? They aren't even able to see it,
so I wonder myself...
さあな 見えもしないのにどうしてんだろうな
Seriously?!
そんな
But, there is one thing I know.
ただな これだけはわかるぜ
That's just the way it is.
There's no way to stop their longing.
そんなもんじゃ あこがれは止められねぇんだ
そだ その兜貸してみ
Oh, I know. Hand me your helmet.
Uh, okay...
What's that thing?
なんだそれは
Didn't I tell you that I'd let you experience it?
言っただろ 体験させてやるよ
That said, you have to promise me!
ただし 約束な
You need to do exactly as I say!
オイラの指示は絶対だ
Can you hear me?
聞こえるか
This is kinda unsettling...
なんだかぞわぞわするな
Nanachi, it feels like you're right next to my ear.
ナナチが耳元にいるみたいだ
Pretty cool, huh?
It's just something I happened to pick up.
すげーだろ 拾いモンだけどな
I can hear your voice,
but where exactly are you, Nanachi?
声はするけど ナナチどこにいるんだ
Don't worry about it. I can see you fine from here.
大丈夫 こっちからは見えてるぜ
Continue going straight.
そのまま前進だ
Understood.
了解した
What?!
なんだ
Hey! Don't needlessly rush in!
おい 無用に突っ込むな
な 子供 馬鹿な
Wha-? A child?!
Ridiculous!
You mustn't come any closer!
こっちに来ちゃいけない だめだ
Don't do it!
That's a Black Whistle.
黒笛だ
Judging by the stuff he was carrying, he was
headed back on his own when he got ambushed.
荷物を見るに単独で戻るところを狙われたな
This is perfect.
丁度いい あの先客を助けてみるか
Wanna try rescuing our new visitor?
O-of course!
とっ 当然だ
Alright, very well, then.
まあいいや
What are you doing?!
何をしてる
いいか 忘れんなよ
Listen, don't forget...
No matter happens, you do exactly as I say.
何があってもオイラの指示通りだ
そうすりゃあタマちゃんも退治できて あいつも助かる
That way you'll be able to dispose of Orby
and the man will be saved.
Where's your reply?
返事は
Understood!
了解した
Alright!
よぉし
Then I'll show it to you now: the world as I see it!
なら見せてやるぜ オイラの見てる世界をなぁ
Okay, to start, look up and completely commit to it.
そいじゃとりあえず
思いっきり上向いてみ
正気か
Are you serious?!
Yep.
ああ いいか 思いっ切りだぞ
Now listen, really commit to it.
し しかし
B-but...
H-hurry and get outta here!
は 早く逃げろ
Don't worry about that guy.
そいつは「気にするな」 あと
Also, stop questioning me!
聞き返すな
My orders are...
オイラのいう事は
...absolute!
絶対
Now jump to the right!
そのまま右側へ飛べ
Irredeemable!
度し難い
You grabbed onto it, I see. Absolutely do not let go.
掴んだな 絶対離すなよ
That thing you've grabbed onto
is the organ it uses to sense the force field.
お前が掴んでいるのは力場を感じ取る器官
That's its lifeline, and without uncoupling
your actions from your conscious mind,
意識と行動を切り離さなきゃ
触ることすらできねぇ奴の生命線だ
you'd never be able to even touch it.
混乱した奴は なりぶり構わず仕留めに来る
Now that it's confused, it'll go for the kill
without any thought of looking graceful.
Now! Tie it up!
今だ 絡めとれ
Its fate is sealed now.
そいつの未来は封じたぜ
Beat it to a pulp!
ぶちかましてやれ
How dare you do that to Riko!
リコを よくも
Huh?
It shed its spines?!
針を捨てた
Damn!
This steam is...!
水蒸気が
D-did it escape?!
に 逃げられた
Well done.
上出来だ
It was forced to eject a full 80 percent of its spines.
It won't be able to hunt here anymore.
八割も針を自切りしたんだ
もうここで狩りはできねぇ
それよか早く戻って来い
More importantly, hurry up and get back here.
H-hey! Don't get too close to him!
お おい そいつに近付くな
Now that Orby is gone, it's cave raiders
that present the most danger to us!
たまちゃんがいなくなった今
オイラたちにとっちゃ一番危険なのが探窟家だぞ
Hey now!
おいったら
What are you...?
君は一体
Could you relay a message for me?
言付けを頼まれてくれないか
Huh?
It's intended for a guy at
Belchero Orphanage named Jiruo.
ベルチェ口孤児院の ジルオという人にあててだ
Jiruo... at Belchero...
ベルチェ口 ジルオ
Tell him that... "We are still continuing our adventure."
「僕らはまだ 冒険を続けている」と
O-okay, got it.
ああ わかった
I'm counting on you.
頼む
I'm sorry.
すまない
Well, you didn't tell him about me,
so I don't really mind...
ま オイラの事言わなかったからいいけどさ
But you sure it'll be alright?
大丈夫なのかよ そのベルチェ口孤児院の奴さ
That, uh, guy at Belchero Orphanage...
お前と繫がりがあるって分かったらやばくね
If people find out he's connected to you somehow,
it could spell trouble.
It'll be fine.
大丈夫だ 一番信頼できる人だから
He's the most dependable guy I know, after all.
In any case, that was pretty amazing, Nanachi!
それにしてもすごかったぞ ナナチ
Using the opponent's own special ability against it
like that was a brilliant strategy!
敵の能力を逆手にとった素晴らしい作戦だ
I wish you'd come with us
to the bottom of the netherworld!
君も奈落の底に付いて来てくれればいいのに
W-well, actually...
あ あのな
I have something to ask of you...
お前に頼みたいこができた
Oh! What is it?!
おぉ なんだ 何でも言ってくれ
You can ask anything of me!
Well...
I knew it would be, but it truly is a hard thing to ask...
さすがに言いずれーんだけどな
Don't hold back!
遠慮はするな
Alright, here it goes.
じゃあ 頼む
'Kay.
ミーティを 殺してくれ
Please kill Mitty for me.
Huh?
Mitty...
ミーティ
Mitty, I'm sorry for running away like this.
ミーティ逃げてごめんよ
I won't just let him...
もうあいつの好きになんか させたりしないから
keep doing as he pleases.
I... I'll figure something out...
んなぁ オイラが オイラが何とかするんだ
Sora ni ukanderu hikaru nami o
空に浮かんでる光る波を束ねて虹の橋をかけよう
Tabanete niji no hashi o kakeyou
危うい足場 滑るスロープ
Ayaui ashiba, suberu slope
Kako to mirai no michishirube
過去と未来の道標
君の左手 僕の右手を
Kimi no hidarite, boku no migite o
Tsunaide tsunagete hajimeyou
繫いで繫げてはじめよう
いつも そばに いるよ
Itsumo soba ni iru yo
過去も 今も 未来も
Kako mo ima mo mirai mo
Dakara mayowazu ni aruiteikou
だから迷わずに歩いていこう
色とりどりの夢 重ねて
Irotoridori no yume kasanete
明日はどこに向かう
Ashita wa doko ni mukau
君と一緒にいれたら 世界は輝きだすよ
Kimi to issho ni iretara, sekai wa kagayakidasu yo
最果ての地に咲く花を探そう
Saihate no chi ni saku hana o sagasou
Next Episode
The Challengers